Katharine Kuh
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Printed Material, 1916-1922, Series 7:; (Boxes 7-10, 13, OV 22; 3.0 linear feet)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous Artists, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Miscellaneous Artists, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous Artists, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous Artists, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Press Releases, 1951-1987, undated, (6 folders) (Box 9, Folder 57-62)
  - Calendars of Events, 1953-1982, undated, (4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
  - Programs, 1958-1991, (7 folders) (Box 10, Folder 5-11)
  - Brochures for Art Schools, 1939-1940, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Brochures for Seminars and Lectures, 1953-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Brochures for the Purchase of Books, 1951-1977, undated, (5 folders) (Box 10, Folder 15-19)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures, 1952-1983, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Booklets Concerning Native American Culture in Alaska, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Booklets Concerning artwork Purchased for the First National Bank of Chicago, 1974, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Booklets Concerning Miscellaneous Art Collections, 1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 23-25)
  - Miscellaneous Booklets, 1967-1988 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Book Poems by Katharine Woolf, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Book of Poetry Many Seasons by Richard Cox, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Book The President by Arthur Secunda, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Training Manual Looking at Modern Art, 1955, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 30-32)
  - Reproductions of artwork, undated, (see also Box 13) (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1966-1979, undated, (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 10, Folder 34-35)
  - Oversize Reproduction of Drawing of Adlai Stevenson, undated (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Antique Map of the 1572 Siege of Haarlem by the Duke of Alba, undated (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Poster for Exhibition by Gordon Onslow-Ford, 1960 (Box OV 22)
  - Oversize Poster for Exhibition by David Hare at Guggenheim Museum, 1977 (Box OV 22)
- Photographs, 1875-1993, Series 8:; (Boxes 10-13; 1.2 linear feet)
  Photographs are of Kuh,including several taken by Will Barnet and Marcel Breuer, family, friends, artists and other colleagues, events, residences, and miscellaneous artwork.
  Photographs of friends and colleagues include an early photo booth portrait of Kuh with Ansel Adams. Other friends and colleagues photographed include Ivan Albright, Alfred Barr, Alexander Calder, Marc Chagall, Willem De Kooning, Edwin Dickinson, Marcel Duchamp, Claire Falkenstein, Alberto Giacometti, poet Robert Graves with Len Lye, Philip Johnson, Gyorgy and Juliet Kepes, Carlos Mérida, José Orozco, Hasan Ozbekhan, Pablo Picasso, Daniel Catton Rich, Carl Sandberg, Ben Shahn, Otto Spaeth, Hedda Sterne, Adlai Stevenson, Clyfford Still, Mark Tobey, and composer Victor Young.
  Group photographs found here include Angelica Archipenko with Kuh; designer Klaus Grabe; José Chavez Morado; Pablo O'Higgins in San Miguel, Mexico; "The Pre-Depressionists" including Lorser Feitelson, Robert Inverarity, Helen Lundeberg, Arthur Millier, Myron Chester Nutting, and Muriel Tyler Nutting; and colleagues gathered for the 1956 Venice Biennale including Peggy Guggenheim, Frances Perkins, and Harry Winston.
  Photographs of events include exhibition installations at the Katharine Kuh Gallery and the Art Institute of Chicago. There are also photographs of exhibition openings that depict Fernand Léger, Man Ray, László Moholy-Nagy at the Art Institute of Chicago, Philip Guston, Jimmy Ernst, Seymour H. Knox, Franz Kline, Robert Motherwell, and Mark Rothko at the Albright-Knox Art Gallery in Buffalo, New York.
  Additional photographs depict three men posing as Léger's "Three Musicians" and the visit of Queen Elizabeth II to the Art Institute of Chicago. There is a photograph by Peter Pollack of an elk skull used as a model by Georgia O'Keeffe. Photographs of artwork include totem poles in Alaska, work by various artists including Claire Falkenstein, Paul Klee, and Hedda Sterne, and work donated to the Guggenheim Museum.
  - Katharine Kuh and Family Members, 1906-1929, undated, (9 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 10, Folder 36-44)
  - Katharine and George Kuh on Honeymoon Trip to Bermuda, at French River, Canada, and on Laurel Avenue, 1930, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 45-46)
  - Katharine and George Kuh, 1931-1932, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 47-49)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1934-1936 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Companion Photo Booth Photographs of Katharine Kuh and Ansel Adams in Chicago, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1937-1939 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1941-1944 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1945-1949 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1950, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 56-58)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1951, (4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 59-62)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1952-1956 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 68-69)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 71-72)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Katharine Kuh and Friends, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Family Members, undated (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Family Members, 1875-1892 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Family Members, 1895-1897 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Family Members, 1917-1928 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Family Members, 1930-1969 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Residences, 1910-1967, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 81-83)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 84-85)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1933-1939 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 1)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1941-1943 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 2)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events: Opening of Exhibition "Modern Art in Advertising," 1945, (2 folders) (Box 11 (hol, Folder 3-4)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1947-1949 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 5)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1951-1952 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 6)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1953-1954 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 7)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1955 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 8)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events: Venice Biennale, 1956, (2 folders) (Box 11 (hol, Folder 9-10)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1957-1959 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 11)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events: Visit by Queen Elizabeth II to the Art Institute of Chicago, 1959, (see also Box 13) (Box 11 (hol, Folder 12)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1960-1963 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 13)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1967-1969 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 14)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1971 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 15)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1975-1978 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 16)
  - Friends, Colleagues, and Events, 1980-1985 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Artists (Box 11 (hol)
    - Ivan Albright, 1959, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 18)
    - Alexander Archipenko, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 19)
    - Fred Berman, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 20)
    - Alexander Calder, 1960-1975 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 21)
    - Frederic Church, 1890 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 22)
    - Edwin Dickinson, 1970 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 23)
    - Marcel Duchamp, 1951, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 24)
    - Claire Falkenstein, 1955, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 25)
    - Lee Gatch, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 26)
    - Alberto Giacommeti, 1956 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 27)
    - Barbara Hepworth, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 28)
    - Karl Knaths, 1928 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 29)
    - Oskar Kokoschka, 1958 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 30)
    - Fernand Léger, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 31)
    - Seymour Lipton, 1963 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 32)
    - Carlos Mérida, 1938-1948, undated, (see also Box 13) (Box 11 (hol, Folder 33)
    - Henry Moore, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 34)
    - José Orozco, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 35)
    - Pablo Picasso, 1954 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 36)
    - Mark Rothko and Christopher Rothko, 1968, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 37)
    - Ben Shahn, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 38)
    - Clyfford Still, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 39)
    - Dorothea Tanning, 1981 (Box 11 (hol, Folder 40)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 41)
  - Exhibition Installations at Katharine Kuh Gallery, Chicago, Illinois, 1938-1940, undated, (see also Box 13) (Box 11 (hol, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition Installation at the Gallery of Art Interpretation, Art Institute of Chicago, undated, (3 folders) (Box 11 (hol, Folder 43-45)
  - Miscellaneous Exhibitions at the Art Institute of Chicago, 1953, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of artwork (Box 11 (hol)
    - By Unidentified Artists, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 47)
    - Totem Poles, undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 48)
    - By Artists with Surnames "A"-"B," undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 49)
    - By Fred Berman, 1990-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11 (hol, Folder 50-51)
    - By Artists with Surnames "C," undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 52)
    - By Artists with Surnames "D," undated (Box 11 (hol, Folder 53)
    - By Artists with Surnames "F," undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 1)
    - By Claire Falkenstein, 1992, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 2)
    - By Artists with Surnames "G"-"K," undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 3)
    - By Paul Klee, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 4)
    - By Artists with Surnames "L"-"M," undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 5)
    - By Artists with Surnames "N"-"O," undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 6)
    - By Artists with Surnames "P, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 7)
    - By Artists with Surnames "R, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 8)
    - By Artists with Surnames "S" undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 9)
    - By Hedda Sterne, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 10)
    - By Artists with Surnames "W," undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 11)
    - Artwork Donated to the Guggenheim Museum, 1983 (Box 12 (pam), Folder 12)
  - Souvenir Set of Photographs of Noto, Sicily, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated, (see also Box 13) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 14)
  - Oversize Photograph of Katharine Kuh by Helen Balfour Morrison, undated (Box 13 (sol))
  - Four Oversize Photographs of the Visit by Queen Elizabeth II to the Art Institute of Chicago, 1959 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Photograph of Carlos Mérida by Peter Pollack, 1948 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Photograph by Edmund Teske of Alexander Archipenko Exhibition Installation at Katharine Kuh Gallery with Kuh, Archipenko, and Carlos Mérida, circa 1938 (Box 13 (sol))
  - Oversize Photograph by Peter Pollack "O'Keeffe's Props," undated (Box 13 (sol))
- Audio Recordings, 1977, Series 9:; (Box 12; 1 folder)
  Four audio recordings on cassette are of Katharine Kuh's lectures, including one about assembling corporate collections, and Daniel Catton Rich reading his own poetry. One tape also contains a recording of the Second Annual Dialogue between Broadcasters and Museum Educators.
  - Audio cassette tapes of Katharine Kuh and Daniel Catton Rich, 1977 (Box 12 (pam), Folder 15)